Sanjeev Sharma

Senior React Js(Next Js) Developer

Over 10 years of IT experience which includes 4 years of Extensive experience as a React JS Developer, 1 year experience as a Next js Developer and 6 years of Experience as a javascript/TypeScript developer. Experienced in MERN stack development Mongo dB, Express, Node, and React.

Extensive experience in developing web pages using HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React JS, Redux,Redux Toolkit, JSON, UNIT Test Case, Node.js, Ajax, JQuery, Bootstrap,Styled Component,Material UI,Ant Design,Tailwind, Formik, Yup. Extensive knowledge in developing single - page applications (SPAs).Good Experience in project configuration using webpack.

Work History

2022-12 - Senior Specialist (Front End) Current

LTIMINDTREE, Noida

- Manage 10 members Front End team and analysed data to identify opportunities for improvement.
- Developed user interface by using React JS, Next JS,
 TypeScript and Tailwind css framework for
 Application development.
- Created Dashboard Using chartJS
- Setup React JS project from scratch using **WebPack**.
- created and validate form using FORMIK and Yup
- Developed team communications and information for meetings.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

2017-04 -2022-12

Team Lead (Front End Development)

Accenture, Gurugram

- Developed user interface by using React JS and Styled Component for Application development.
- Developed Application by using MERN Stack
 Development .
- Design, develop and test HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap,

Contact

Address

Noida, UP 201306

Phone

995-863-6753

E-mail

sanjeevcs44@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sanjeev-sharmab586871

Skills

React Js

Upper intermediate

Next Js

TypeScript

Javascript

Upper intermediate

Redux



Upper intermediate

Redux Toolkit



WebPack

JavaScript, jQuery and React JS that meets accessibility and web browser standards for website.

- Worked as lead frontend developer to develop product from scratch.
- Led projects and analysed data to identify opportunities for improvement.
- Developed team communications and information for meetings.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

2015-09 -Front End Developer

2017-04

2015-09

Narvar, Noida

- Designed dynamic and **multi-browser** compatible pages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Developer responsive interface using **Bootstrap** and used SASS for CSS.
- Responsible for creating screens with table-less designs meeting W3C standards.
- Responsible for front-end UI design using **HTML5**, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery plugins.
- Used **Media Queries** for design to be compatible in all devices.
- Developed different **iQuery** component in **MVC** framework.
- Used **Dreamweaver** as editor for designing new pages.
- Used **Grunt** as task runner to test **JavaScript** with JSHint.
- Worked on Cross-Browser Compatibility and tested each & every web application on popular web browsers such as Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, Opera and Chrome.

2013-05 -Senior Software Engineer Web Design

Xavient Information System, Noida

- Designed web pages by using HTML, XHTML, CSS and deploy script using with JavaScript.
- Developed secured web applications by using client scripting such as JavaScript and JQuery.
- Involved in software coding, testing, and debugging for web presentation layer using **HTML** and **CSS**.

Upper intermediate

GraphQL

Upper intermediate

REST API

Upper intermediate

CSS/FlexBox

Upper intermediate

Material UI

Upper intermediate

TailWind

Upper intermediate

Antd Framwork

Upper intermediate

Formik N Yup

Intermediate

Styled Component

Upper intermediate

JIRA

Intermediate

VS Code

Elementary

GIT

Intermediate

PostMan

Upper intermediate

- Developed application logos and images by using
 Adobe Photoshop CS3 and Illustrator.
- Designed graphic objects, illustrations, images (vector and bitmap) and banners with using Adobe
 Flash, Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator.
- Developed user interactive web applications and Rich Internet Applications (RIAs) using with help of Adobe Dreamweaver.
- Developed E-commerce enterprise applications
 using web technologies like HTML, DHTML, XHTML,
 DOM, PHP Script, JSP Script and CSS based on W3C
 standards.

Frontend framework design

0000

Upper intermediate

Front End Web Development

> ●●●● Upper intermediate

Front-end supervision

Front End Code Analysis



Upper intermediate

Education

2002-04 - Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science
2006-06 SRIT - Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh